So ETB devices.
This will show the list of devices attached to the machine.
So in this case I have only the emulator running here.
So if you have multiple emulators or multiple devices attached to your PC, it will be displayed here.
So if you want to restart ADB as a root, then you could use this command ADB root, so it's already
running as a root.
And then if you want to start the server, you can use this command.
So it's already running.
So let's stop it.
It stops our server.
So this will kill the server and now ADB devices, they are not running.
Now it's starting at this one.
So it has restarted it again.
So let's kill it once again.
So when you type ADB devices again, it's basically restarting it.
So the kill server is used to kill the ADB server and ADB start server is used to start it.
So now it has a starter.
Now if you want to reboot the emulator or the device, you could use ADB Reboot Command.
So this will reboot the emulator to take seconds.
Okay.
So now the emulator is restarting.
So now it is up and running.
Now ADB devices list.
This will show some more information about the product and the model.
So if you simply type device, it will show this information.
So if you put an L, you'll get all this information.
Then if you want to get into the shell, ADB shell, so this will get into the shell of this emulator.
And from here you could type it command, for example.
So this will give you the ID of the UID of the current user.
And if you want the superuser rights just type issue, then you become the super user.
And from here you can do many other operations from here.
For example, the SES command this okay so this will dump the system services details and once you dump
it then you can extract it out of the emulator for your analysis.
So similarly, there are a lot of other commands which you could run from the shell and to exit from
the shell you can just type exit.
And if you want to explore more, just try using the help.
So this will give you the list of commands supported.
So in this case, I have connected two devices.
So one is a mobile phone and another is this emulator.
So I have a device and an emulator connected.
So in this case, if you type ADB Shell, then it says that more than one device or emulator.
So how can you connect to the emulator now?
So if you want to connect to emulator, what you need to do is ADB shell, hyphen e shell.
So this will connect to the emulator.
It just need to pass hyphen e stands for emulator and if you need to connect to the device, you can
you can simply give the for device.
Then you kind of get connected to the phone or any other device which you have connected to.
And in case if you have multiple devices or multiple emulators, then how would I connect to the shell
or execute some other ADB command?
So in that case, you could use the serial number like here it would be devices.
So here you get the serial number.
So this is the serial number.
So you could say ADB, shell, iPhone SE and here you could simply copy and paste this serial number.
Then it will connect to the device so you can pass the serial number directly here.
Hyphen is the serial number.
If I need to connect to the emulator, then I could simply pass the serial number from here.
This is the serial number.
So now I'm connected to emulator.
So this is pretty handy when you work a lot with many devices.